[Music]
Hello everyone and welcome to this
business central launch event session on
managing PTEES in the admin
center. Um starting this release wave
we'll start surfacing the PTEs that are
installed on your environments in the
admin center and in the admin center API
which enables you to automate across
them. Let's jump straight into a demo.
I'm here in the business central admin
center um looking at my sandbox
environment and just as before I can
click apps in the top here to get a list
of my apps. What's new here is that
there's now a drop down. So whereas
before we would only show global apps,
we can now also see PTEES and dev
extensions. So let's have a look at
PTEES. You can see here that that in my
tenant right now there's one PTE. Uh if
you would have more, they would all be
showing here and you can uninstall them
straight from here as well. Um going
back to the global apps, you also notice
that there's a new uninstall action for
these apps. So for the apps that can be
uninstalled, which is almost all of them
with exceptions, just as base app, um
you can now click uninstall and um
decide to uninstall this app straight
from the admin center. For apps that
don't have any dependencies, you simply
choose whether you want to keep the
application data or not. So if I choose
yes, the extension would be uninstalled
and also the data would be deleted. If I
uh leave this then the data would remain
so that I can um use it should I
reinstall this extension at a later
point. What's also new here is that if
I'm uninstalling an app that has
dependencies, I can now see those
dependencies right in the admin center.
So for example here I have the E
document core app which is three apps
that depend on it. Uh meaning that I
cannot uninstall this app without
uninstalling these three as well. So
you're warned that this will happen if
you uninstall this app. Again, I can
choose to delete the application, yes or
no. Um, and then I can confirm that I'm
okay with uninstalling all the dependent
apps along with the app that I intended
to
uninstall. That concludes the demo of
viewing the um PTEES in the admin
center. Um, there's a few things that
are good to know as we're shipping this
functionality. Uh, everything that I
just demoed in the admin center will
also be available in the admin center
API from version 2.25. Uh specifically,
we're introducing a new uninstall
requirements endpoint. This is an
endpoint that you can use to see which
apps would be uninstalled if you decide
to uninstall an app that has downstream
dependencies. And secondly, there's new
properties on the app's endpoint. For
example, to see um the app type of the
app that is returned by this
endpoint. That concludes this learning
session on the PTS in the admin center.
Thank you for watching.